Squiggly and squirty!
♪♪｢にょろにょろ
ぴゅるぴゅる ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞ｣
Mayonnaise.
Damn light yellow stuff!
♪♪｢薄黄色の憎いﾔﾂ｣
Yummy, yummy.
♪♪｢おいしい おいしい ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞ｣
Mayonnaise.
Eggs and vinegar and oil!
♪♪｢卵と酢と油｣
Naturally delicious on salad!
♪♪｢ｻﾗﾀﾞにかけると当然おいしい｣
Still great when sucked
straight from the bottle!
♪♪｢そのまま吸っても
やっぱりｲｹる｣
♪♪｢完全 奇跡 料理を蹂躙
ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞ！｣
A perfect miracle!!
Revolutionizes cooking!
Mayonnaise!
やあ みんな！ 今日も元気に…｡
Hey, everyone!
Is everybody doing slurpingly well today?
すすりこんでるかい？
ﾏﾖﾘｰﾝからのお知らせだよ｡
Here's an announcement from Mayorin!
ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞが どうやって生まれて➡
Does anybody want to know where mayonnaise
comes from and how it gets to you?
どうやって
みんなのところに届くか➡
知りたい人は いるかな？
なんと 今なら
３万個に１つのﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞに入ってる➡
Guess what?
Whoever finds a ticket, 1 in every 30,000 bottles,
gets an invitation to Mayorin's home!
ﾁｹｯﾄを見つけた人を
ﾏﾖﾘｰﾝのお家に ご招待！
ﾏﾖ好きのみんな どんどんすすって
このﾁｹｯﾄを見つけてね！
Mayo lovers should suck
away to find a ticket!
I'll be waiting!
待ってるよ！
That was a squishy message for your dinner
table from Mayorin Mayonnaise.
[ﾓﾆﾀ]以上 お客様の食卓を
ﾄﾞﾛｯと演出する➡
ﾏﾖﾘｰﾝ ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞでした｡
ｱﾊﾊｯ！ ｱﾊｱﾊ ﾊﾊｯ！
ﾏﾖ… ﾘｰﾝ｡
Mayo...rin...
["Hometowns and Boobs are
Best Thought From Afar"]
(土方)そんなわけで本日より➡
And so starting today, amendment
25 to bureau policy,
局中法度 二十五条
追加項目として➡
as you can see,
このとおり 一人一日
五ﾏﾖの消費を義務づける！
Less than Five Mayonnaise a Day is Unacceptable.
requires each person to consume
five bottles of mayonnaise a day!
(みんな)えぇ～!?
What?!
Shut up!
うるせぇ！ 副長命令だぞ！
This is an order from your
Vice-commander!
What is this?
おいおい！ いきなり
呼び出されたと思ったら➡
We were told to assemble on short
notice for the sake of this order?
なんだよ この命令！
Maybe the Vice-commander's lost his mind
after eating too much mayonnaise...
副長 ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞの食べすぎで
頭が おかしくなったんじゃ…｡
Hijikata-san.
(沖田)土方さん｡
なんだ？ 総悟｡
What is it, Sogo?
Well, I don't know what you're plotting,
あの… どういう魂胆か
知りやせんが➡
but I can't understand why the rest of us
have to go along with your mayo fetish.
さすがに ｱﾝﾀのﾏﾖ好きにまで➡
みんな つきあわされる道理が
わからねえ｡
あん!?
つうか それ➡
Eh?
'Sides, it's got nothing to do
with the samurai code.
士道 まったく関係ねえし｡
Yeah! Yeah!
そうだそうだ！
いくら副長でも これは横暴だ！
This is oppressive, even
for the Vice-commander!
Toshi, when you decide something, you need to
explain it in a way that everyone else can accept.
(近藤)ﾄｼ いくら
お前の決めたこととはいえ➡
これは みんなに
納得がいく説明をしてやらんと…｡
ﾁｯ！ おい 山崎
みんなに説明してやれ｡
This is too much even for...
Hey, Yamazaki.
Explain this to everyone.
Huh?!
(山崎)えっ!? あっ… い いや｡
U-Uh, no, but...
あの ｵﾚ
何も聞いてないんですけど…｡
You never told me anything...
つうか むしろｵﾚが説明を
聞いてみたいな みたいな…｡
In fact, I'd like to have this explained
to me, you know...?
おい 殺すぞ｡
Hey, I'll kill you.
Listen up, you morons!
おい ﾊﾞｶ野郎ども！
この大不況時に➡
Ya' think keeping the streets safe is enough for us
Shinsengumi during the time of this great recession?!
ｵﾚら真撰組が
治安を守るためなだけで➡
許されると思ってるのか!!
景気も守らねえといけねえんだよ｡
We need to keep the economy safe too!
Gotta do our part in building
domestic demand!
内需拡大に貢献しろ！
ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞ消費しまくって景気回復！
Consume lots of mayonnaise
to help the economy recover!
Our organization needs to appeal
to the public in multiple ways!
ｵﾚらは 市民にあらゆる面で
愛される組織であらなくては➡
ならねえんだよ！
わかったか野郎ども!!
You got that, fools?!
はい よくできました｡
Okay, good job.
Everybody who understands
should applaud.
理解できた人は 拍手｡
Applause!
拍手！
遠慮すんな ﾃﾞｻﾞｰﾄもあるぞ｡
Don't hold back.
There's still dessert.
Squiggly and squirty!
Mayonnaise.
Damn light yellow stuff!
Damn it!
ｸｿｯ！
Squiggly and squirty!
Mayonnaise.
Damn light yellow stuff!
I can't find one...
当たらねえ！
Get that mayonnaise away from me!
ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞを近づけんじゃねえ!!
Ketchup... Ketchup is better...
ｹﾁｬｯﾌﾟ… ｹﾁｬｯﾌﾟのほうがいい…｡
Everybody! Have you already
found your tickets?
みんな もうﾁｹｯﾄは見つけたかな？
There's only a little more time until
the deadline for invitation tickets.
ご招待ﾁｹｯﾄの受付〆切りまで
あと少しだよ｡
Hurry, hurry!
急いで 急いで～！
[ﾓﾆﾀ]以上 お客様の食卓をﾇﾙﾃｶさせる
ﾏﾖﾘｰﾝ ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞでした｡
That was a smooth and shiny message for your
dinner table from Mayorin Mayonnaise.
《何でだ 何で当たらねえんだよ》
Why...?
Why can't I find one...?!
(山崎)なんじゃこりゃ～っ！
What the hell?!
どうした 山崎！
What's wrong, Yamazaki?!
副長！ 見てくださいよこれを！
Vice-commander, please look at this!
I was squeezing mayonnaise out
when a weird piece of paper...
ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞ絞ってたら
なんか 中から変な紙が｡
Th-This is!
《こ これは～っ！
きた～っ！》
This is it!!
どうします？ これ｡
異物混入でﾒｰｶｰに電話したほうが｡
What do we do with this?
We should probably call the manufacturer
to complain about a foreign object...
Ya-Yamazaki, that's...
山崎 それ…｡
えっ？
おめでとう｡ よかったな 山崎｡
Congratulations.
Huh?
Isn't that great, Yamazaki?
これで
ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞ工場へ行けるらしいぜ｡
You can go to the mayonnaise
factory now.
えっ？
あれ 土方さん顔色が悪いね｡
Huh?
Oh? You look pale, Hijikata-san.
あれ？ まさか自分が
ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞ工場行きたいがために➡
What? Did you force everybody to eat mayonnaise
because you wanted to go to the factory?
みんなにﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞ
無理やり食べさせてたとか？
ﾁｹｯﾄ当てたﾔﾂから横取りしてでも｡
Even if it means taking away someone
else's winning ticket?
な なわけねえだろ ﾊﾞｶ野郎！
内需拡大のためだって➡
O-Of course not, you fool!
We said that it was to help
build domestic demand!
言っただろうが！
H-He figured it out!
《ﾊﾞﾚてる！》
That's good to hear.
そりゃよかった｡
まさか副長ともあろうお方が➡
I couldn't imagine that the Vice-commander would
take a winning ticket from a subordinate.
部下の当たりくじを取り上げる
なんて ありえねえですし｡
じゃあ ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞ工場
楽しんでこいよ 山崎｡
Then go have fun at the mayonnaise
factory, Yamazaki.
な なんかよくわからないけど➡
I-I don't really understand...
これ喜んどいたほうが
いいのかな？
Should I be happy about this...?
山崎 ﾃﾒｴ ﾎﾝﾄ ﾃﾒｴ ﾏｼﾞでﾃﾒｴ…｡
Yamazaki, you...
You're really...
No, really...
おめでとう 山崎！
Congrats, Yamazaki!
You're scaring me!
《怖え～っ！》
Uh, you can have this if you'd like...
あの もし よければ
これ 差し上げますけど｡
It's too late for that now!
んなこと今さら
できるわけねえだろ！
'Cause you're the one who found it!
当てたのはお前なんだし｡
お前が行くのが筋だし｡
'Cause it's only natural for you to go!
ﾏﾖﾘｰﾝもきっと
お前のこと待ってるし！
'Cause I'm sure Mayorin
is waiting for you!!
おい そんなに意地をはるな ﾄｼ｡
Hey, don't be so stubborn, Toshi.
Eggs...
近藤さん｡
Kondo-san...
お前が誰よりも
ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞを愛してることは➡
Everybody knows your
love for mayonnaise.
みんな知ってるさ｡
みんな今回のことも どこかしら
気づいて つき合ってたんだ｡
And we went along kind of knowing
what this was all about.
だから そのﾁｹｯﾄ
ここにいる全員の気持と思って➡
So think of that ticket as our
blessing and accept it.
受け取ってもらえないか｡
Vice-commander...
副長…｡
かたじけねえ｡
みんな かたじけねえ｡
Thank you...
All of you... Thank you so much...
ｺﾞﾘ… いや近藤さん｡
Gori...
I mean, Kondo-san.
(近藤)あれ？
今 ｺﾞﾘﾗって言いかけなかった？
Huh? Were you about to say Gorilla?
いいこと言ったのに
ｺﾞﾘﾗって言いかけなかった？
After I said all those nice things, you
were about to call me Gorilla?
[Mayorin Mayonnaise Factory]
[A few days later]
では特別見学の方
次の工程へご案内します｡
Now then, members of the special field
trip, I shall take you to the next step.
今回 おみやげに
ﾏﾖﾈｰｽﾞもらえるらしいよ｡
I heard that we get mayonnaise
as a souvenir this time!
All right!
やった！
やっぱ最新の設備はｽｹﾞｴな！
These new facilities are amazing!
本日はご苦労様でした｡
Thank you for visiting today.
ﾏｰ ﾏｰ…｡
Ma-, Ma-...
ﾏﾖﾘｰﾝ…｡
Mayorin...
どこ？
Where are you?
(銀時)あぁ… もう
勘弁してくれよ！
Ah, man. Give me a break already.
なんで こんなむさ苦しい格好
しなくちゃならねえんだよ!?
Why do I have to wear
this suffocating thing?
ﾊﾟﾝﾂが ｹﾂにはりついて
もう 半端ねえんだけど｡
My underwear is stuck
to my ass like crazy.
ｹﾂなのか ﾊﾟﾝﾂなのか｡
It's all like, is that my underwear
or my ass?
Like I'm it and it's me.
おれがあいつで あいつがおれで
みたいになってるんだけど！
We don't have a choice.
(新八)しようがないでしょ！
It'll get ugly if we don't go in prepared.
ちゃんと武装しとかないと
えらいことになりますよ｡
Would you rather be killed
or have sticky underwear?
殺されるのと ﾊﾟﾝﾂはりつくのと
どっちがいいんですか？
Getting rid of a beehive?
ﾊﾁの巣の駆除ってよ なんつう仕事
引き受けてるんだよ｡
Why did you accept this job?
And from what I heard, we're up against
their violent brothers, the wasps.
しかも 聞いたところによると➡
相手は あの暴君
ｽｽﾞﾒﾊﾞﾁ先輩らしいじゃないっすか｡
It'll be fine.
大丈夫ですよ｡
ちゃんと武装してきたんだから｡
Since we came in full gear.
お前… ｽｽﾞﾒﾊﾞﾁ先輩
なめてんじゃねえぞ｡
Hey, don't underestimate those wasps.
They're nothing like those soft honey
bees making their high school debut.
ﾐﾂﾊﾞﾁなんて 高校ﾃﾞﾋﾞｭｰしたての
ｱﾏちゃんとは 格が違うんだよ｡
先輩はな
ｺﾅの運び屋だけじゃ飽き足らず➡
These big guys aren't satisfied
by transporting pollen.
[Pollen]
They even carry out hits.
殺し屋の仕事もやってんだぜ｡
It'd be no problem for them to raid
another school in small numbers,
他の学校に
２～３人で ｶﾁｺﾐに行って➡
and end up slaughtering them all.
生徒 全滅させるのも
わけないからね｡
They don't care if they knew you
back in middle school.
同じ中学だったﾔﾂも関係なしだよ｡
しかも 学園のﾏﾄﾞﾝﾅ はらませて➡
Not to mention impregnate the school madonna and
raise the young by feeding them the corpses.
そのｶﾞｷに
死体 食わせて 養ってんだぜ｡
They're devils.
ほとんど 悪魔だよ｡ ﾏｼﾞ パねえよ｡
Insane bastards.
そのｽｽﾞﾒﾊﾞﾁ先輩の家
壊しにいくなんて➡
And we're crazy enough to
go destroy their home?
正気の沙汰じゃねえよ！
There's still time.
今からでも遅くねえよ｡
Let's buy some soba and sake and give
them a warm welcome to the hood.
そばと酒 買ってきて
引っ越し祝いに切り替えようや！
(神楽)情けないｱﾙな｡
相手は たかが ﾊﾁｱﾙよ ﾊﾁ｡
Pathetic.
They're just a bunch of bees. Bees.
They might be big,
but that's only relative.
でかいって いったって
ﾊﾁの中の話ね｡
ｽｽﾞﾒｱﾙよ｡
本当ですよ｡
Seriously...
あぁ 万事屋さんですか｡
こっちです こっち｡
Ah, are you Odd Jobs?
Over here, over here.
Ah, sorry to keep you waiting.
あっ どうも お待たせしました｡
すみませんね
わざわざ ご足労いただいて｡
I apologize about making you
come all the way out here.
いや あれなんですけどね｡
Well, that's the one I mentioned.
いつのまにか作ってたみたいで…｡
なんとか なります？
It just popped up when I wasn't looking...
Can you do something about it?
["The Whole Peeing on a Bee Sting Is
a Myth. You'll Get Germs, So Don't Do It!!]
どうですかね？ まぁ こちらは
全部 お任せしますが…｡
How does it look?
Well, I'll leave it up to you...
お任せって なんだよ？
ﾌｨｰﾘﾝｸﾞｶｯﾌﾟﾙか!?
What's that supposed to mean?
Are we playing "Feeling Couple" here?!
[Note: From a 70's dating game show
called "Propose Daisakusen"]
そのまま ２人で 愛の巣 新築か？
Are the two of us supposed
to build a love nest now?!
あれの どこが ｽｽﾞﾒの巣なんだ？
ｻﾗﾏﾝﾀﾞｰの巣の間違いだろうが!!
How is that a beehive?!
More like a salamander nest!
す… すみません いや 昨日までは
何もなかったんですけどね｡
F-Forgive me!
But, there wasn't anything
there last night.
一夜にして あちこち
あんなのが できてまして｡
These popped up all over
the place overnight.
どこの世界に 一夜にして
こんな巣を作るﾊﾁがいるんだよ！
What kind of world would have bees that
could build a nest like that in one night?
Is the queen a slave driver?
女王ﾊﾞﾁ どんだけ ｽﾊﾟﾙﾀ？
You shouldn't be talking when
you don't even pay us.
給料 払えてない お前に
言われたくないね｡
Master Monk, I'm sorry to say
that this isn't from Earth.
住職さん 残念ながら
これ 地球産じゃないですよ｡
It's an alien species.
外来種ですね｡ 危険すぎます｡
ﾎﾞｸらの手には負えませんよ｡
It's too dangerous.
We can't handle it.
そこを なんとかお願いします｡
Could you please deal with it?
私も こういう職業なんでね｡
Consider my occupation...
殺生とかは
ちょっと あれなんですよ｡
I couldn't take a life.
人間は死んでもいいのか!?
But you're okay with humans dying?
You're okay with us being incinerated
by salamanders?!
ｻﾗﾏﾝﾀﾞｰに
焼き尽くされてもいいのか!?
This will be a nuisance to the
neighbors if I leave it alone.
このまま いったら 近隣にも
迷惑がかかるし お願いします｡
I beg of you.
私らも応援しますんで｡
祈り 捧げますんで｡
We shall also cheer you on.
We shall pray for you.
Stop the chanting!
お経はやめろ！ 縁起でもねえ!!
That's bad luck!
あ… じゃあ
ﾗｯﾌﾟなら ありってことで｡
Then rap should be okay.
Hey!
おい！ ﾗｯﾌﾟだったら
やってくれるってよ｡
They'll do it if we rap!
Ah, hey! Wait!
あ… おい！ 待て!! 何 勝手に…｡
What are you...
どうしましょう？
ﾗｼﾞｶｾ 取りに行っちゃいましたよ｡
Right, there was a tape.
Yeah, yeah!
What do we do?
They went to get a tape deck.
帰るぞ｡
We're leaving.
Who knows how big the
bees in that thing are?
こんなもん どれだけ でかいﾊﾁが
出てくるか わからんぞ｡
防護服なんて 何の意味もねえよ！
ﾌﾞｯｽﾘ いかれたら おしまいだよ｡
These protective suits won't do a damn.
It'll be over if they plunge into us.
But what will happen to the
monks if we just ignore it?
でも このまま ほっといたら
お坊さんたち どうなるんですか？
Don't worry about it.
大丈夫だよ
坊主とﾊﾁは 相性いいんだから➡
Monks and bees get along
well so they'll be fine.
うまく やってけるよ｡
ﾏｶﾞｼﾞﾝでもやってたろ 『ﾎﾞｰｽﾞﾋﾞｰ』｡
[Bouzu = Monk]
Didn't Shonen Magazine
have a "BOUZU BEE"?
No, that was "BOYS BE..."
いや 『BOYS BE…』です｡
どっちも似たようなもんだろ｡
Same difference.
It's that manga where everyone's
crotch stinger is twitching, right?
股間の針 腫らしてる漫画だろ？
ﾎｱﾁｬｰ！
終わったｱﾙ｡
It's over.
(神楽)何やってるｱﾙか？
ねぇ 銀ちゃん！ 新八！
What are you doing?
Hey, Gin-chan, Shinpachi.
Don't talk to me!
《ｵﾚに話しかけるな!!
ｵﾚは なんにも知りません！
I know nothing at all!
あのﾊﾞｶとは 一切 関わりのない
ただの腐った死体です！
I'm a rotting corpse who has
nothing to do with that fool!
刺しても 何も いいこと
ありませんから 腐ってますから》
Nothing good will come of stinging me!
I'm just a rotting corpse!
Gin-san!
銀さん！ ﾊﾁに死んだふりって
効くんですか!?
Does playing dead work against bees?!
I've never heard of anyone doing that!
Are you sure about this?!
聞いたことないんですけど
大丈夫なんですか!? これ！
Is it going to work?!
いけるんですか!? これ！
話しかけんじゃねえ！
Don't talk to me!
Do you wanna die?!
殺されてぇのか!? つうか なんで
坊さんどもまで やってんだよ！
And why are the monks
also playing dead?!
あっ！ ﾃﾒｴ!!
Hey!
How dare you play dead by
yourself after talking to me?!
話しかけといて 何 ﾃﾒｴだけ
本格的に死んだふりしてんだ!!
[Please take good care of the garden.]
あれ？ なんか 妙に静かですね…｡
Huh?
It's awfully quiet...
銀ちゃん
こっから どうするｱﾙか？
Gin-chan, what do we do next?
あり？ 襲ってくる気配がねえぞ｡
Huh? I don't sense anything
coming to attack us.
普通 あんだけのことしたら
怒って 出てきますよね｡
Normally, they would come swarming out
in a rage after that much of a mess.
なんか 大丈夫そうだな｡
I guess we should be safe.
おい これ もともと➡
Hey, maybe this wasn't a
beehive to begin with?
ﾊﾁの巣なんかじゃ
なかったんじゃねえのか？
え？
Huh?
I mean, who's ever heard
of such a huge beehive?
だって そもそも
こんなでけぇ ﾊﾁの巣➡
あるわけねえじゃん｡
じゃ
いったい なんなんですか？ これ｡
Then what is this?
誰かのｲﾀｽﾞﾗ？ あの住職
ﾛｸなもんじゃなかっただろ｡
A prank?
That monk didn't seem very nice.
きっと 近隣の住民に
嫌われてんだよ｡
The neighbors probably hate him.
ﾅﾒたことしてんじゃねえよ！
Don't mess with us!
こっちも
ﾋﾏじゃねえんだよ ﾊﾞｶﾔﾛｰ！
We don't have time for this crap, damn it!
ちょ… ２人とも！
Hey! You two!
あ～あ…｡
Oh dear...
(ﾊｯﾁ)何してんの？ お兄さん｡
い… いや…｡
Whatcha doing, big guy?
Uh...
Don't give me that crap. I asked
what you were doing.
いや やのうて
今 何したって聞いとるんじゃ｡
Yeah... Sorry.
あの すみません｡ ひ… 人が…
ﾊﾁがいるとは思わなかったんで…｡
I didn't realize that there were
people...bees inside.
あ そう｡
ほな ﾊﾁがいなかったら➡
I see.
So it's okay to kick a bee house
if there aren't any bees inside?
ﾊﾁんち 蹴ってもええ
いうことかい｡
N-No... Huh?
い… いや… え？ ﾊﾁ？
ﾊﾁですよね？
Bee?
So you're a bee?
ﾊﾁなんですよね？ やっぱり…｡
So you're actually a bee?
Hey, boss!
(ﾘｷ)あ～ ｱﾆｷ！
支柱 ﾎﾟｯｷﾘ いかれてますわ！
The support's snapped in half!
No, you've got it wrong.
いや 違います｡
それ ｵﾚじゃなくて ｺｲﾂが…｡
That wasn't me, it was her...
So the earthquake was your doing?!
さっきの地震も ﾃﾒｴらの仕業か！
(ﾊｯﾁ)ちょっと 事務所まで
来てもらおうか お兄さんたち｡
Could you come down
to the office with us?
H-Hold on! Hold on!
ちょ… ちょっと待って！
ちょっと待って！ 違うんです！
You've got it wrong!
Coming through!
(神楽)おじゃましますよ｡
おじゃましますじゃねえだろ！
Coming through, my ass!
Whose fault do you think this is?!
誰のせいで
こうなったと思ってんだ！
すんませ～ん！ ﾊﾁﾐﾂ おかわり！
Excuse me, more honey!
改めて どうも｡
ﾛｲﾔﾙｾﾞﾘｰ星の若頭 ﾊｯﾁいいます｡
Allow me to introduce myself.
I'm the young head of planet
Royal Jelly, Hacchi (Bee).
さて… どう ﾅｼつけましょ｡
Well then, we need to have a talk.
どない
落とし前つけるつもりじゃ！
How ya gonna pay up for this?!
One or two stingers won't be enough!
針の１本や２本つめるどこじゃ
済まへんで！
Actually, we don't have
stingers to begin with.
いや もともと ないんで…｡
Uh, I don't know about your
planetary customs,
あの… そちらの星は
どういう風習か存じませんけど➡
地球では ﾊﾁの巣は 見つけ次第
安全面を考慮して➡
but on Earth, we make a practice of eliminating
beehives for safety purposes.
即 撤去する風習に
なってまして…｡
ほな 何かい？ 人の星で 勝手に
巣 作った わしらが悪い と？
And?
It's our fault for building a nest on someone
else's planet without permission?
I wouldn't say that it's your fault...
悪いっていうか…
人里 離れたところだったら➡
Nobody would mind if you made hives
away from residential areas...
じゃんじゃん 作ってもらって
かまわないんですけど…｡ ﾋｯ！
I've also got something to say to you.
ほな 言わせてもらいまっけど
どいてほしいんなら➡
If you want us to leave,
shouldn't you ask?
どいてくれって 口で言うたら
ええんとちゃいますの？
Using force without even trying
to talk things through...
話のひとつもせんと
暴力で訴えかけてくるなんて➡
Isn't that how the yakuza would behave?
まるで ﾔｸｻﾞのやり口やないですか｡
ほんま 怖いところやで 地球は｡
Earth is a damn scary place.
それに わしら怒ってんのは
別に 巣 壊されたことちゃうで｡
And we aren't angry about
our hive being ruined.
巣は また 若い衆に作らせりゃ
元に戻る｡
The youngins will have it back
to normal in no time.
だが 世の中には 二度と➡
But some things in this world
will never come back.
取り返しのつかないもん
っちゅうのがあるんです｡
That earthquake sent our Lady on
her way to the hive in the sky.
(ﾊｯﾁ)さっきの地震で
わしらのｱﾈさん➡
天に召されてけつかんねん｡
ﾀﾝｽから 旧式 ＱＳ３落ちてきて
ｷｭﾚｲｽﾃｰｼｮﾝどころか➡
The old QS3 fell out of the dresser.
[Note: Parody of PlayStation 3]
Forget about Qlaystation...
She's been sent to a completely
different station!
まったく別のｽﾃｰｼｮﾝに
旅立ってしもうてん！
How you gonna make up for this?!
どないしてくれるんじゃ～っ！
ﾒｽは ｱﾈさんしかおらんのじゃ～！
The Lady was our only female!
わしらは みんな ｱﾈさんの息子！
We were all her sons!
The Queen Bee dying is the
same as the planet dying!
女王ﾊﾞﾁが死ぬ いうんはな
星が滅ぶのと同じことなんじゃ！
I'm gonna stab you all dead!
お前ら全員 刺し殺したらぁ！
Stab every Earthling dead
and destroy this planet!
地球人全員 刺し殺して
この星も滅ぼしたらぁ！
Stop that, Riki.
やめねえか ﾘｷ！
せやかて ｱﾆｷ！
But boss!
You were the one who bought
this QS3 at Akihabara!
(ﾊｯﾁ)ＱＳ３ ｱｷﾊﾞで
買うてきたんは お前やろが！
せやから 言うたやないか！
ＱＳ３は ごっつ重いから➡
Didn't I tell you?!
Be careful because the
QS3 is damn heavy!
気ぃつけって！ ＱＳＰのほうが
ええんちゃうかって！
The QSP is better!
(ﾘｷ)せやかて ｱﾆｷも 『ﾁﾐｷｽ』
ごっつ見てはりましたやん！
But boss! You were also obsessed
with ChimiKiss!
[Note: Parody of PS2 dating
game KimiKiss.]
You so wanted to play that thing!
ごっつやりたそうに
してはりましたやん！
ChimiKiss was on QS2!
(ﾊｯﾁ)『ﾁﾐｷｽ』は ＱＳ２です！
ＱＳ３ではありません！
Not QS3!
Besides, I wouldn't bother
with that pussy crap!
そもそも そない軟弱なもん
わしが見るわけないやろ！
It was Fetal Gear!
[Note: Parody of the Metal Gear Series.]
あれは 『ﾍﾀﾚｷﾞｱ』じゃ！
(ﾘｷ)『ﾍﾀﾚｷﾞｱ』は ＱＳ３です！
Fetal Gear was on QS3!
Too bad!
残念でした！
ｳｿじゃ～！ 『ﾁﾐｷｽ』じゃ！
Liar! It was Chimi Kiss!
What's wrong with Chimi Kiss?!
『ﾁﾐｷｽ』の何が悪いんじゃ！
『ﾍﾞﾗｶﾞﾐ』も最高じゃ！
Berakami was also great!
[Note: Parody of PS2 dating
game Amagami.]
Now, now, enough of that.
まぁまぁまぁ
そのへんにしときぃ｡
Have some honey and calm
down, for crying out loud.
ほら ﾊﾁﾐﾂ飲んで
ちょっと落ち着きぃな｡
ほんまに もう…｡
ｹﾝｶしたら あかんよ｡
すんまへん｡
No more fighting, you hear?
Sorry.
やばい… やばいよ…
どうすんですか 銀さん｡
This is bad.
Bad.
What do we do, Gin-san?
どうすんですか…｡
What do we do?
Uh...
あの… 要は 女王ﾊﾞﾁさえ
なんとかすれば➡
So you won't need to destroy our planet if
we do something about your queen, right?
星は滅びなくて済む
ってことですよね？
Gotcha.
わかりました｡ 責任とって
ｵﾚたちが なんとかします｡
We'll be responsible for that.
そのかわり 女王ﾊﾞﾁなんとかしたら
こっから出てってもらいますよ｡
In return, you'll leave if we patch
up your queen, yeah?
(ﾊｯﾁ)なんや？ ｱﾈさん
生き返らせられるとでも➡
What?! You're saying that you
can bring the Lady back?!
いうんかい！
(ﾘｷ)できひんかったら この星➡
You know what's gonna happen
to this planet if you fail!
どうなるか わかってるんやろな！
おう ｺﾗ！
銀さん… いったい
どうするつもりなんですか？
Gin-san, what do you intend to do?
星の命運まで
背負いこんじゃいましたよ｡
The fate of the planet is in our hands.
心配いらねえ｡ 手はある｡
Don't worry.
There's a way.
女王ﾊﾞﾁを他から見繕ってくる｡
はぁ!?
We just have to find another queen.
Huh?
忘れたか？
Did you forget?
These popped up all over
the place overnight.
((一夜にして あちこちに
あんなものができまして…))
That wasn't the only hive
built on these grounds.
境内にできた巣は
あれ ひとつじゃねえ｡
We'll talk to the other hives and
ask if their queens can help out.
他の巣にかけあって➡
女王ﾊﾞﾁに ｱｲﾂらの面倒も
見てくれるよう 頼んでくる｡
Is that possible?!
そんなことできるんですか!?
ｽｽﾞﾒﾊﾞﾁは 同じ中学だったﾔﾂも➡
Didn't you say that wasps didn't hesitate to beat
up others who were in the same middle school?!
関係なく潰すって
言ってたじゃないですか！
交渉の材料として
ﾊﾁﾐﾂを たっぷり持ってきた｡
I brought plenty of honey
for negotiating purposes.
They won't turn us away.
悪い顔はしねえはずだ｡
よ～し！ じゃあ 行ってくるね！
Okay, I'm off then!
Wait!
待て～っ！ お前は黙って
ﾊﾁﾐﾂ飲んでろ｡
You keep quiet and drink your honey.
すみません！ ﾛｲﾔﾙｾﾞﾘｰ星の使いで
参った者なんですけど！
Excuse me!
We were sent by Planet Royal Jelly!
Huh? Are they out?
あれ？ いないのかな？ 花粉でも
取りにいったんですかね？
Did they go to harvest pollen?
I'll go take a look.
ちょっと見てくる｡
ちゃっちゃと終わらせてくるわ｡
Get this over with in a jiffy.
ｵﾒｴら 余計なことすんじゃねえぞ｡
じっとしてろ｡
You guys better not do anything dumb.
Sit tight.
Especially you, Kagura.
特に神楽！ お前は
微動だにするんじゃねえぞ｡
Don't even twitch.
お前が動くと
ﾛｸなことねえからな！
Nothing good happens when you move.
すんませ～ん！ ﾊﾁﾐﾂ おかわり！
Excuse me, more honey!
あの どないしてくれるんでしょ？
わしらのｱﾈさん…｡
Uh...
How are you going to make up for
what's happened to our Lady?
(ﾏｻ)殺したろか！
お前ら ほんまに殺したろか！
You killed her!
You actually killed her!
Wait. Calm down, Masa.
待て！ 落ち着け ﾏｻ｡
古い ＺＢＯＸ買いにいったんは➡
You were the one who
bought an old Zbox!
[Note: Parody of Xbox]
お前やろ！
せやから 言うたやないか！
Didn't I tell you?!
Be careful because the
Zbox is damn heavy!
ＺＢＯＸは ごっつ重いから
気をつけって！ ＴＳのほうが➡
The TS is better!
[Note: Parody of Nintendo DS]
ええんちゃうかって！
(ﾏｻ)せやかて ｱﾆｷも➡
But boss, you were also obsessed
with iDOLM@SKER!
[Note: Parody of Xbox 360
game iDOLM@STER]
『ｱｲﾄﾞﾙﾏｽｶｰ』ごっつ
見てはりましたやん！
You so wanted to play that thing!
ごっつ やりたそうに
してはりましたやん！
Who would bother with pussy
crap like IM@S?!
誰が 『ｱｲﾏｽ』なんて軟弱なもん
見るか！ 『ｷﾞｱｰｽﾞｵﾌﾞｺﾞｯﾄﾞ』じゃ！
It was Gears of God!
[Note: Parody of Xbox360
game Gears of War]
You're obviously an IM@S fan when
you know the abbreviation!
『ｱｲﾏｽ』略してる時点で
『ｱｲﾏｽ』ﾏﾆｱですやん！
銀さ～んっ！ どうすんですか!?
Gin-san!
What are we going to do?!
Another hive!
巣を！ 早く 他の巣を探せ～っ！
Find another hive quick!
This is no good!
ﾀﾞﾒだこりゃ～っ！
あ！ まだ 息がある！
She's still breathing!
That's it!
そうか！ Oweeは 他のｹﾞｰﾑ機より
軽いから 軽傷で済んだんだ｡
The Owee is lighter than the other consoles,
so she was only slightly injured!
[Note: Parody of Nintendo Wii]
Hang in there, queen lady!
しっかりしてください！
どこぞの女王ﾊﾞﾁさん！
おい 頼む！
ｱﾝﾀ ﾊﾁども ひとつにまとめて➡
C'mon, we're beggin' you!
Can you take care of all those bees?!
世話してやってくんねえか！
おい 死ぬな～っ！
Hey, don't die!
You're the only one left!
もう ｱﾝﾀしかいねえんだ！
気になって ついてきてみれば➡
I followed you because I was worried,
and I've run into our blood enemies!
こないなところで
とんだ天敵と遭遇じゃ｡
Planet Royal Pudding!
ﾛｲﾔﾙﾌﾟﾘﾝ星！
お前ら 地球に何しにきたんじゃ！
Why did you come to Earth?!
ﾛｲﾔﾙｾﾞﾘｰ星！
まさか ｱﾝﾀらも ここを狙って!?
Planet Royal Jelly!
You were also targeting this place?!
なるほど… 皆 狙いは
同じ いうわけじゃ｡
I see...
Everybody was after the same thing.
(ﾊｯﾁ)ﾛｲﾔﾙﾖｰｸﾞﾙﾄ星!?
Planet Royal Yogurt?!
There was someone else to deal with
before we conquered this planet
この星 征服するには
地球人を駆逐する前に➡
倒さなあかん相手が
おったようじゃな｡
and exterminated the human race.
渡さへん！
You aren't getting this!
誰にも渡さへんで！
I'm not letting anyone touch this!
You fools...
お前らなんかに…｡
The QS3...!
ＱＳ３は！
ＺＢＯＸは！
Oweeは！
The Zbox...!
The Owee...!
(みんな)渡さへんでぇ～っ！
...is ours!
On that day, what started
as a beehive removal
＜ その日 ﾎﾞｸらは
ﾊﾁの巣を駆除するつもりが➡
３つの星を滅ぼした｡
turned into the destruction
of three planets.
はからずも 彼らの地球征服を
阻止したﾎﾞｸたちだったが➡
We inadvertently stopped their
attempts to conquer Earth,
その心は 決して
晴れやかなものじゃなかった｡
but it wasn't anything to feel good about.
ﾊﾁの巣ひとつといえど そこには
星ひとつと なんら変わらない➡
One beehive
is the same as an entire planet.
無数の命の重みがあった｡
It shouldered the burden
of countless lives.
ﾎﾞｸらの命は 夜空に輝く➡
Our lives were built upon as many lives
as there were stars in the night sky.
あの星の数ほどの命の上に
支えられていた＞
Yo！ 万事屋さん！
ﾗｯﾌﾟの用意 できましたけど？
Yo, Odd Jobs!
We ready to rap.
Huh? You're already done?
あれ？ もう終わっちゃいました？
お経でいい｡
え？
Chant away.
Huh?
ﾔﾂらのために お経を…
唱えてやってくれるか？
Would you say a prayer for their sake?
To all living creatures in this universe...
全宇宙 生きとし生ける者たちへ｡
(３人)ﾅｰﾑｰ｡
Namu.
ｳﾁの若い衆 見当たらんのやけど
知らへん？
You know where they went?
Not the slightest.
知らへん｡ ほなことより
ｸｲｰﾝｱﾗｺﾞｽﾀ 狩りにいかへん？
Anyway, wanna go hunt
down Queen Aragosta?
[Note: Parody of Queen Rangosta from Monster
Hunter Portable 2nd G for the PSP]
Let's, let's.
行こ 行こ｡
生きてんじゃん｡
They're alive.
Next time:
"Beware of Foreshadows."
Is that meant for me?
[There is a "death flag" which signifies that you will die.
And once you think everything is right and well...]
[Yuden raises the deathflag and viciously
sets out to get revenge.]
[See you next time.]
♬『ゼッコーチョー！』
♬～